Jonathan Stewart

Manager/St. Louis VMUG Leader/vExpert/Cisco Champion

stewmanchu@hotmail.com

Summary

I have been working in the Information Technology environment for over 15 years from troubleshooting and providing customer support to managing a team of 20 technicians providing support to over 3,000 computers in over 200 classrooms.

I primarily focus on cloud computing and the benefits thereof, including virtualizing the datacenter but also virtualizing desktops and applications. I focus on designing the proper solution for each job and do it in a quick manner. I work well with deadlines and managing both people and resources.

Specialties: CompTIA A+, Network+, Security+, Project+, Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA), Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (MCSE), Microsoft Certified Information Technology Professional (MCITP): Enterprise Administrator, Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist: Windows 7, VMware Certified Professional (VCP 4), VMware Certified Professional - Datacenter (VCP-DCV), VMware Certified Associate - Cloud (VCA-Cloud 5)

Experience

Leader at St. Louis VMUG

June 2014 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Local Co-leader of the St. Louis VMware User Group. Leads VMUG meetings and arranges vBeers to promote VMware and virtualization in the St. Louis area. Other co-leaders include Marc Crawford and Mike Masters.

Manager at Enterprise Holdings

September 2016 - Present (1 month)

Responsible for managing the execution of product development strategies as defined by Product Management, in addition to interfacing with Operations Management to ensure VMware, Cisco, EMC, and VCE support strategies are streamlined and seamless. Responsible for determining time and resources needed to complete assignments, and assist team members in prioritizing and completing assigned tasks and projects where needed. Responsible for vendor management, and people management activities, including career planning/support, training, interviewing, hiring, rewarding, disciplining, and performance and salary reviews.

Sr. Systems Engineer at Enterprise Holdings

January 2014 - September 2016 (2 years 9 months)

Responsible for designing, developing, testing, implementing, maintaining, and supporting moderately complex components of the systems infrastructure. Evaluates and integrates software and hardware requests. Provides issue and problem resolution for moderately complex issues and performs disaster recovery exercises. Provides instruction and guidance to less senior team members on new tasks and assignments. Performed 6-month tour of duty with the Public Cloud Framework team, assisting them with implementing security regulations to the linux applications that reside in Amazon Web Services. During this time, learned python and was able to co-architect Splunk solution. Also used javascript to connect JIRA ticket button to Jive site. Utilized Confluence to document work as well as tie in tickets from JIRA.

Lead, Sr. Systems Engineer - SaaS at Lumeris

February 2012 - January 2014 (2 years)

Team lead for Virtualization, Applications and Server Administration for Lumeris - Software as a Service. Handle Infrastructure for products like Maestro, Nimble, ClearPractice, and FACETs.

Sr. Systems Administrator at ClearPractice

October 2011 - March 2012 (6 months)

Aid in planning, implementing, and deploying ClearPractice's technology infrastructure. Responsible for ensuring high availability across all systems and applications along with remediation as required. Provide technical support and troubleshooting for the entire technical infrastructure.

Site Lead at L3 MPRI

September 2008 - October 2011 (3 years 2 months)

Lead a team of 21 people to oversee training network for the EN, MP, and CBRN schools to include the simulation network.

Network Support Technician at General Dynamics Information Technology

July 2006 - September 2008 (2 years 3 months)

Worked as Server Administrator with 49 servers and six domains. Kept antivirus up-to-date, maintained 50+ SharePoint sites, as well as upkeep of over 1500 users and close to 800 computers.

Self Employed as Consultant at Self Employed

November 2005 - May 2006 (7 months)

Provided troubleshooting and consulting to various customers on both PCs and Apple computers as well as providing printer support.

Certifications

MCITP: Enterprise Administrator on Windows Server 2008

Microsoft July 2010

MCTS: Windows Server 2008 Applications Infrastructure, Configuration

Microsoft July 2010

MCTS: Windows Server 2008 Network Infrastructure, Configuration

Microsoft July 2010

MCTS: Windows Server 2008 Active Directory, Configuration

Microsoft July 2010

MCTS: Windows 7, Configuration

Microsoft June 2010

MCSA: Windows Server 2008

Microsoft April 2012

MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional

Microsoft April 2012

MCSE1: Windows Server 2003

Microsoft May 2010

MCSA1: Windows Server 2003

Microsoft July 2006

MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional

Microsoft November 2005

VMware Certified Associate - Cloud (VCA5-CMA)

VMware License VMW-00327252H-00068204 January 2014

CompTIA A

CompTIA License E9YFKFR2QLFEC4HV October 2005

CompTIA Network

CompTIA License 1BZM8C5ECPF4K5WN June 2006

CompTIA Project

CompTIA License BJT38DKM23E1Q8TN September 2009

CompTIA Security (2008 edition)

CompTIA License 0QSVLSW1SHF4Y2P2 June 2009

Projects

Develop Cloud Infrastructure Capacity Usage vCOps Custom UI Dashboards for EHI

December 2013 to March 2014

Members:Jonathan Stewart, Peter Tymbel, Max Drury

Propose a plan and get management's approval for developing custom VMware vCenter Operations Manager dashboards to address inherent product limitations

- # Work with the cloud management team to identify the requirements and build use cases for cloud capacity usage reporting
- # Identify and analyze data gathering and reporting gaps in VMware vCenter Operations Manager vSphere UI
- # Create conceptual designs and wireframes for new capacity usage dashboards
- # Select appropriate widgets to display detail-rich matrix views and charts
- # Create custom super metrics to mathematically derive data not collected natively by vCOps in order to augment existing statistics and enable visualization of other dimensions useful for capacity usage reporting
- # Customize and tailor widgets to display relevant objects, metrics, super metrics, and charts

- # Create interaction between various widgets to dynamically filter metrics based on selected objects
- # Create custom XML to dynamically drive charts based on selected objects and/or metrics
- # The culmination of this work are the following dashboards:
- # Cloud Capacity Scoreboard
- # Cloud Storage Capacity
- # Cloud Compute Capacity
- # Cloud Memory Capacity

VCE Vblock and VMware vCloud Director Upgrade for EHI

February 2014 to Present

Members: Jonathan Stewart, Peter Tymbel, Max Drury, JJ Soto, Michael Keiser, Rick Wilcox, Joseph Chapie

- # Work with security team to identify security gaps in the Vblock physical infrastructure, cloud and virtualization stacks
- # Develop project and engineering plans for addressing identified security gaps and requirements
- # Use VCE Release Certification Matrix (RCM) to identify Vblock components that need upgrades and to what versions
- # Identify and map-out dependencies among the RCM, cloud and virtualization stacks
- # Create a Matrix Upgrade Order of Operations based on the RCM, but tailored to the Enterprise specific implementation of VMware vCloud Director in the Internal Private Cloud (IPC)
- # Create level of effort estimate for time and resources needed to accomplish the Matrix Upgrade
- # Create and document detailed step-by-step upgrade procedures for all Vblock components, cloud and virtualization stacks
- # Leverage cloud team's talent to divide and conquer Matrix Upgrade into manageable tasks
- # Test upgrade procedures in lab to identify bugs and validate the upgrade procedures

VMware vCloud Automation Center (vCAC) POC

May 2014 to Present

Members: Jonathan Stewart, Peter Tymbel, Max Drury

Implement VMware vCloud Automation Center (vCAC) 6.0 Proof of Concept (POC) in lab for testing and product evaluation.

- # Review vCAC deployment documentation
- # Plan and document vCAC POC design and Architecture
- # Deploy vCAC Identity Appliance (SSO)
- # Deploy vCAC Appliance
- # Deploy vCAC IaaS Component on Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2
- # Implement Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 database for IaaS
- # Integrate with Active Directory
- # Admin Portal Config
- # Create Initial Tenant
- # Configure new vSphere cluster for use with vCAC
- # Add vSphere Endpoint

- # Define a Fabric Group
- # Define a Business Group
- # Create Reservation Policies
- # Create Network Profiles
- # Create Resource Reservations

VMware vCloud Director 5.5 Upgrade for EHI

May 2014 to Present

Members: Jonathan Stewart, Peter Tymbel, Max Drury

Upgrade VMware vCloud Director and vCloud Networking and Security 5.1 to 5.5 in production Internal Private Cloud environment.

NSX/vRealize/ITBM/vROPs lab

August 2015 to Present

Members: Jonathan Stewart, Max Drury, Michael Keiser, Rick Wilcox

Lab Objectives

The lab will be used as the basis for design and training area for all the various technologies that will be used in the planned strategy. The components will be:

- # vRealize Automation Center
- # vRealize Orchestrator
- # vRealize Operations Manager & Log Insight
- # vRealize Business Standard
- # NSX

Key Lab Functions:

Training ground for team to learn and try out new products/features.

Ability to showcase key technologies to team and/or leadership

Lab Deliverables

The lab will provide the following capabilities as it is built out:

- # Ability to demonstrate Multi-Tenancy with role based access
- # Blueprint's for basic OS versions of Windows & RHEL
- # Network Feature Virtualization
- # Chargeback capabilities
- # Performance Management and advanced logging.
- # Service Now Integration
- # High level design documentation

Internal Cloud Platform Refresh

June 2016 to Present

Members:Jonathan Stewart, Max Drury, Michael Keiser, Rick Wilcox, Jeremy Jones, Anthony Schulte, Nathan Storm, Lance Iverson

The primary goals of this Internal Private Cloud (IPC) Refresh project are to refresh End-Of-Life (EOL) VBlock/VMware hardware/software, migrate existing IPC workloads to the new VBlock, reclaim storage capacity consumed in Shared Services, and iterate on new IPC feature set (TBD based on customer feedback).

Volunteer Experience

Youth Pastor at First Assembly of God, St. Robert

January 2002 - April 2008

Skills & Expertise

VMware

Active Directory

Disaster Recovery

Virtualization

Servers

SharePoint

Data Center

Troubleshooting

Cloud Computing

Technical Support

Windows 7

Management

Microsoft Certified Professional

Hardware

Windows Server

VMware ESX

DNS

Linux

DHCP

SaaS

System Administration

Leadership

Operating Systems

Microsoft Office

Powershell

Microsoft Exchange

Visio

Lync

Enterprise Architecture

IIS

vSphere

ThinApp

IT Operations

IT Management

VCP5

VCP4

Microsoft

Vmware View

Certifications

Team Management

MCSE

MCITP:EA

Network+ Certified

Security+ Certified

Project+ Certified

Confluence and JIRA

vRealize Automation

Cloud Computing IaaS

HTML

CSS

Education

Southwestern Assemblies of God University

B.S., Church Ministries, 1996 - 1999

Southeast Missouri State University

1993 - 1995

Battle Mountain High School

1989 - 1993

Languages

English

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

French

(Elementary proficiency)

Organizations

St. Louis VMware User Group

Co-Leader

July 2014 to Present

Honors and Awards

vExpert 2015

VMware Communities

August 2015

The VMware vExpert program is VMware's global evangelism and advocacy program. The awards are for individuals, not companies, and last for one year. Employees of both customers and partners can receive the awards.

https://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vexpert

Cisco Champion 2016

Cisco Communities

January 2016

Cisco Champions are a group of highly influential IT technical experts who enjoy sharing their knowledge, expertise, and thoughts across the social web and with Cisco. The Cisco Champion program encompasses a diverse set of areas such as Data Center, Internet of Things, Enterprise Networks, Collaboration, and Security. Cisco Champions are located all over the world.

vExpert 2016

VMware Communities

February 2016

The VMware vExpert program is VMware's global evangelism and advocacy program. The awards are for individuals, not companies, and last for one year. Employees of both customers and partners can receive the awards.

https://communities.vmware.com/community/vmtn/vexpert

Courses

Sr. Systems Engineer

Enterprise Holdings

VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, and Manage [V6]

VMware NSX: Install, Configure, Manage [v6.0]

VMware Cloud Orchestration and Extensibility [V6.1] VMware vSphere: Troubleshooting Workshop [V5.5]

VMware vSphere: Optimize and Scale [V5.5]

VMware vCenter Orchestrator: Develop Workflows

[V5.1]

Jonathan Stewart

Manager/St. Louis VMUG Leader/vExpert/Cisco Champion

stewmanchu@hotmail.com



4 person has recommended Jonathan

"I had the pleasure of working with Jonathan for about two years between General Dynamics and MPRI. He was a great leader and always had innovative ideas. He was always there to help with problems whenever he could. He led me in the right direction to become successful in my position at MPRI."

— Wendy Wilson, PMP, reported to Jonathan at L3 MPRI

"Jonathan and I have worked together for the last year and a half. Jonathan takes a team approach to the job that is refreshing and productive. He sees everyone as a valued player in day to day operations. Jonathan is very knowledgeable and competent in all almost all aspects of our job including Active Directory, VMWare, Linux, scripting, programming, networking, database management, SharePoint, etc.... He also has great people skills, a good sense of humor, and motivation to get the job done. Jonathan is a very competent manager who looks out for the well being of those who work under him and the company."

— Bryce S., reported to Jonathan at L3 MPRI

"Jonathan is the consummate IT leader. He has technical skills that are second to none, exceptional leadership abilities, skilled at integrating IT and military training, purposeful direction, and a great ability to create a team where each person not only has the opportunity to contribute but to excel at and enhance their IT and teamwork skills. It's a comfort to know the ship is under control of such a competent captain. His friendly demeanor and humor only enhance his already top-notch leadership qualities."

— Nick Burchett, reported to Jonathan at L3 MPRI

"Jonathan is a very detailed manager. He knows how to implement all the projects and dispatches us in a timely fashion to perform those projects."

— **David Wigton**, reported to Jonathan at L3 MPRI

Contact Jonathan on LinkedIn